<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="4.3.2">Jekyll</generator><link href="https://databrut.com/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="https://databrut.com/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2023-07-12T20:50:20+02:00</updated><id>https://databrut.com/feed.xml</id><title type="html">DataBrut - AI Partner+</title><subtitle>Transforming Businesses Through Strategic Software Consultancy</subtitle><author><name>Ilija Lazarevic</name></author><entry><title type="html">Technology and Social Disruption</title><link href="https://databrut.com/lectures/2023/07/04/dos-impact-on-serbia-and-the-region/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Technology and Social Disruption" /><published>2023-07-04T00:00:00+02:00</published><updated>2023-07-04T00:00:00+02:00</updated><id>https://databrut.com/lectures/2023/07/04/dos-impact-on-serbia-and-the-region</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://databrut.com/lectures/2023/07/04/dos-impact-on-serbia-and-the-region/"><![CDATA[<p>Last week, we at DataBrut had the opportunity to participate in a “<em>Digital Open Society (DOS) Technology and Social Disruption: Impact on Serbia and the Region</em>” seminar organized by the Friedrich Naumann Stiftung on subjects related to recent AI advancements and using them to improve lives in various spheres of work. We have been following these advancements and researching potential uses in some domains of usage. However, by participating in this seminar workshop, we gained insights into how participants from different spheres perceive AI in general, recent advancements in the industry (e.g., ChatGPT), and potential challenges, outcomes, and solutions.</p>

<p>On these two days, lecturers tried to bring us closer to the technology behind AI and introduced many interesting questions and ideas. Having in mind our involvement in the technology testing and researching potential uses, the most inspiring and thought-provoking was the second day of the seminar, where speakers talked about how AI should be regulated and how putting recent AI technologies, like ChatGPT, into practice can affect privacy, copyrights, labor, security, and much more.</p>

<p>In the end, all of us should be aware that AI, while becoming more and more powerful every day and with more and more super useful functionalities, is still nowhere near Artificial General Intelligence (AGI). And although it is far away from AGI and what we call <em>singularity</em>, it still introduces interesting use cases and brings concerns of different sorts to the world we know and live in. It is worth mentioning that even the greatest minds in this domain are expressing concerns about how AI is used and how we should carefully guide and regulate its use.</p>

<p>Check out this TED talk given by Garry Marcus, a psychologist and cognitive scientist and emeritus professor at New York University. He is one of the advocates for AI regulation, and a critic of the “hype” surrounding AI.</p>

<p><br /></p>

<div style="max-width:854px"><div style="position:relative;height:0;padding-bottom:56.25%"><iframe src="https://embed.ted.com/talks/lang/en/gary_marcus_the_urgent_risks_of_runaway_ai_and_what_to_do_about_them" width="854" height="480" style="position:absolute;left:0;top:0;width:100%;height:100%" frameborder="0" scrolling="no" allowfullscreen=""></iframe></div></div>]]></content><author><name>Ilija Lazarevic</name></author><category term="[&quot;lectures&quot;]" /><category term="workshop" /><category term="ai" /><category term="conference" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Last week, we at DataBrut had the opportunity to participate in a “Digital Open Society (DOS) Technology and Social Disruption: Impact on Serbia and the Region” seminar organized by the Friedrich Naumann Stiftung on subjects related to recent AI advancements and using them to improve lives in various spheres of work. We have been following these advancements and researching potential uses in some domains of usage. However, by participating in this seminar workshop, we gained insights into how participants from different spheres perceive AI in general, recent advancements in the industry (e.g., ChatGPT), and potential challenges, outcomes, and solutions.]]></summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://databrut.com/assets/img/dos-serbia.jpg" /><media:content medium="image" url="https://databrut.com/assets/img/dos-serbia.jpg" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Talk at ML Conference 2023, Serbia</title><link href="https://databrut.com/talk/2023/05/22/ml-conference-2023-talk/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Talk at ML Conference 2023, Serbia" /><published>2023-05-22T00:00:00+02:00</published><updated>2023-05-22T00:00:00+02:00</updated><id>https://databrut.com/talk/2023/05/22/ml-conference-2023-talk</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://databrut.com/talk/2023/05/22/ml-conference-2023-talk/"><![CDATA[<p>Last week, we had the privilege of participating in the highly anticipated ML Conference 2023, held in Palic, Serbia. The conference proved to be an incredible experience, filled with insightful workshops, engaging talks, and valuable networking opportunities. We are thrilled to share our reflections on this exceptional event.</p>

<h2 id="zeroth-day-workshop-and-basics-of-data-science">Zeroth Day Workshop and Basics of Data Science</h2>
<p>Prior to the conference, we took part in the enlightening zeroth day workshop dedicated to future students. During this workshop, we had the opportunity to impart the basics of Data Science, providing the attendees with a comprehensive understanding of this rapidly evolving field. It was rewarding to share our knowledge and contribute to inspiring the next generation of AI enthusiasts.</p>

<h2 id="conference-day-a-delightful-blend-of-learning-and-networking">Conference Day: A Delightful Blend of Learning and Networking</h2>
<p>On the 18th of May, the conference day arrived, and we were filled with excitement. The day was nothing short of delightful, as we immersed ourselves in the engaging talks and connected with professionals from diverse backgrounds and industries. Networking with colleagues and forging new connections proved invaluable, allowing us to exchange ideas, learn from each other, and strengthen our professional network.</p>

<h2 id="our-talk-real-estate-and-property-price-prediction">Our Talk: “Real Estate and Property Price Prediction”</h2>
<p>The second day of the conference was particularly invigorating for us, as we had the opportunity to present our own talk titled “Real Estate and Property Price Prediction.” This talk enabled us to showcase our domain expertise and share insights on the application of data science in the real estate industry. The interactive Q&amp;A session that followed allowed for enriching discussions and provided valuable takeaways for both the audience and ourselves.</p>

<h2 id="gratitude-for-an-unforgettable-experience">Gratitude for an Unforgettable Experience:</h2>
<p>In conclusion, our participation in ML Conference 2023 was an incredible journey that left a lasting impression. We extend our heartfelt gratitude to the organizers for inviting us to speak at this prestigious conference in Serbia. The opportunity to contribute, learn, and connect with professionals in the field was truly invaluable. We return from the conference with newfound knowledge, renewed inspiration, and an unwavering commitment to further advancing the field of AI and data science.</p>

<p>As we reflect on this wonderful experience, we eagerly look forward to future conferences and opportunities to share our expertise, collaborate with industry peers, and continue pushing the boundaries of AI innovation.</p>]]></content><author><name>Ilija Lazarevic</name></author><category term="[&quot;talk&quot;]" /><category term="real estate" /><category term="data science" /><category term="conference" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Last week, we had the privilege of participating in the highly anticipated ML Conference 2023, held in Palic, Serbia. The conference proved to be an incredible experience, filled with insightful workshops, engaging talks, and valuable networking opportunities. We are thrilled to share our reflections on this exceptional event.]]></summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://databrut.com/assets/img/blog-2023-05-22-ml-conference-2023-talk.jpeg" /><media:content medium="image" url="https://databrut.com/assets/img/blog-2023-05-22-ml-conference-2023-talk.jpeg" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Workshop at ML Conference 2023. at Subotica, Serbia</title><link href="https://databrut.com/lectures/2023/05/18/workshop-ml-conference-2023/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Workshop at ML Conference 2023. at Subotica, Serbia" /><published>2023-05-18T00:00:00+02:00</published><updated>2023-05-18T00:00:00+02:00</updated><id>https://databrut.com/lectures/2023/05/18/workshop-ml-conference-2023</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://databrut.com/lectures/2023/05/18/workshop-ml-conference-2023/"><![CDATA[<p>We are thrilled to share our exciting experience participating in the “zeroth” day of the ML Conference 2023, held in Palic, Serbia. Collaborating with DataKolektiv, we had the honor of delivering a captivating lecture that served as an introduction to the fascinating world of Data Science. Our primary audience consisted of high school students, and it was a joy to share insights and ignite their passion for AI and machine learning.</p>

<h2 id="conveying-general-ideas-about-data-science">Conveying General Ideas about Data Science</h2>
<p>During our lecture, we had the opportunity to delve into the fundamental concepts of Data Science, providing the students with a glimpse into this rapidly evolving field. We discussed the significance of data and how it drives innovation, as well as the powerful role of machine learning in uncovering patterns and making accurate predictions. By conveying the general ideas and principles of Data Science, we aimed to inspire the students to explore this exciting domain further and consider pursuing a career in AI.</p>

<h2 id="fostering-passion-for-ai">Fostering Passion for AI</h2>
<p>Witnessing the enthusiasm and engagement of the high school students during our talk was truly rewarding. We hope that our lecture served as a catalyst for their continued exploration of Data Science and AI. By igniting their passion for AI at an early stage, we aim to inspire them to pursue further education, attend related workshops and conferences, and ultimately become the next generation of AI innovators and thought leaders.</p>]]></content><author><name>Ilija Lazarevic</name></author><category term="[&quot;lectures&quot;]" /><category term="workshop" /><category term="data science" /><category term="conference" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[We are thrilled to share our exciting experience participating in the “zeroth” day of the ML Conference 2023, held in Palic, Serbia. Collaborating with DataKolektiv, we had the honor of delivering a captivating lecture that served as an introduction to the fascinating world of Data Science. Our primary audience consisted of high school students, and it was a joy to share insights and ignite their passion for AI and machine learning.]]></summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://databrut.com/assets/img/blog-2023-05-18-workshop-ml-conference-2023.jpeg" /><media:content medium="image" url="https://databrut.com/assets/img/blog-2023-05-18-workshop-ml-conference-2023.jpeg" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Meetup at Digitalna Inicijativa Srbije</title><link href="https://databrut.com/meetups/2023/05/17/meetup-at-dsi/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Meetup at Digitalna Inicijativa Srbije" /><published>2023-05-17T00:00:00+02:00</published><updated>2023-05-17T00:00:00+02:00</updated><id>https://databrut.com/meetups/2023/05/17/meetup-at-dsi</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://databrut.com/meetups/2023/05/17/meetup-at-dsi/"><![CDATA[<p>In a recent enlightening talk, we explored the exciting realm of automated price prediction for the real estate industry and how data science and AI can revolutionize the valuation process. With a focus on assisting real estate valuers in obtaining accurate information, we delved into the advantages and challenges associated with both full and automated valuation processes. This blog post aims to provide a comprehensive overview of the key insights shared during the talk, shedding light on the potential of AI-driven solutions in real estate valuation.</p>

<h2 id="advantages-and-disadvantages-of-full-and-automated-valuations">Advantages and Disadvantages of Full and Automated Valuations</h2>
<p>During the talk, we examined the benefits and limitations of both full and automated valuation processes, particularly in the context of desktop valuations. We emphasized the market approach as a prominent method used in automated valuations. However, challenges persist across marketplaces, with a notable issue being the time lag between property sales and the availability of comparable data from institutions. This delay poses a considerable hurdle for both full and desktop valuations, making the overall valuation process more complex. Furthermore, transparency emerged as a significant challenge, particularly in developing and undeveloped countries where robust market data can be scarce.</p>

<h2 id="approaches-in-modeling-automated-valuation-models-avms">Approaches in Modeling Automated Valuation Models (AVMs)</h2>
<p>One key aspect of the talk focused on exploring various modeling approaches for Automated Valuation Models (AVMs). Our discussion primarily revolved around an effective approach utilizing regression boosted trees. By employing this methodology, we demonstrated how AVMs can deliver improved accuracy and reliability in predicting property prices. Leveraging data science techniques and AI algorithms, AVMs offer valuable support to real estate valuers, streamlining the valuation process and providing insights that complement their expertise.</p>

<h2 id="results-and-the-quest-for-fully-autonomous-avms">Results and the Quest for Fully Autonomous AVMs</h2>
<p>Presenting the results of our research, we acknowledged that although AVMs are considered autonomous by definition, efforts are still underway to achieve full autonomy. While the current outcomes of AVMs show promise, they still fall slightly short of the detailed reports provided by certified valuers. Nevertheless, AVMs can serve as powerful tools to augment the full valuation process, enhancing efficiency and enabling valuers to make well-informed decisions. As technology advances and methodologies evolve, we strive to bridge the gap and propel AVMs towards achieving full autonomy while continuously improving their accuracy and reliability.</p>

<h2 id="conclusion">Conclusion</h2>
<p>The captivating talk on automated price prediction for the real estate industry highlighted the significant role data science and AI can play in assisting real estate valuers. By overcoming challenges related to lagging data availability and transparency, AVMs have emerged as invaluable resources in the valuation process. While our quest for fully autonomous AVMs continues, the integration of AVMs in full valuations offers a powerful approach to enhance the efficiency and effectiveness of the real estate valuation process. As the industry embraces AI-driven solutions, we anticipate remarkable advancements in real estate valuations, leading to more accurate, transparent, and data-informed decisions.</p>]]></content><author><name>Ilija Lazarevic</name></author><category term="[&quot;meetups&quot;]" /><category term="real estate" /><category term="data science" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[In a recent enlightening talk, we explored the exciting realm of automated price prediction for the real estate industry and how data science and AI can revolutionize the valuation process. With a focus on assisting real estate valuers in obtaining accurate information, we delved into the advantages and challenges associated with both full and automated valuation processes. This blog post aims to provide a comprehensive overview of the key insights shared during the talk, shedding light on the potential of AI-driven solutions in real estate valuation.]]></summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://databrut.com/assets/img/blog-2023-05-17-meetup-at-dsi.jpeg" /><media:content medium="image" url="https://databrut.com/assets/img/blog-2023-05-17-meetup-at-dsi.jpeg" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry></feed>