<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>DataBrut - Consultancy</title>
    <description>Ilija Lazarevic - M.Sc.IT
</description>
    <link>http://www.databrut.com/</link>
    <atom:link href="http://www.databrut.com/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <pubDate>Wed, 14 Jun 2023 15:38:39 -0500</pubDate>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 14 Jun 2023 15:38:39 -0500</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>Jekyll v3.9.2</generator>
    
      <item>
        <title>Long awaited update</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Hey,&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s been a while! At least, that is what is said.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This blog was created with the intention of sharing my experiences working as a consultant for the field of software and machine learning engineering. I suppose because I was so intent on doing my job well that this blog was neglected. I’m going to fix that.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There was a lot going on in the time frame of the preceding year. I worked on a project that was closed down, spoke at a conference, and got the notion to launch a new business.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In next posts, I’ll go into more detail about each of these topics. Well, while I write about everyday things that intrigue me and make me want to rant about them.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Let’s begin!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 14 Jun 2023 15:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://www.databrut.com/intro/2023/06/14/long-awaited-update.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.databrut.com/intro/2023/06/14/long-awaited-update.html</guid>
        
        <category>intro</category>
        
        
        <category>intro</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Great beggining</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Welcome,&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This web site is going to be kind of a blog where I will post my content related to the domain of Artificial Inteligence, Data Science and Machine Learning.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I will also write about other interesting things, like my harp playing hobby, interest to capture interesting surroundings on my phone camera and so on.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Hope you will like it and if you like it, feel free to follow and contact me.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Cheers!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sun, 15 May 2022 06:55:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://www.databrut.com/intro/2022/05/15/start.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.databrut.com/intro/2022/05/15/start.html</guid>
        
        <category>intro</category>
        
        
        <category>intro</category>
        
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
